<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Economist: Europe</title>
    <description>Europe</description>
    <link>http://www.economist.com</link>
    <image>
      <link>http://www.economist.com</link>
      <width>125</width>
      <title>Economist.com</title>
      <url>//media.economist.com/sites/all/themes/econfinal/images/the-economist-logo.gif</url>
      <height>34</height>
    </image>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 13:18:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <webMaster>robertscurr@economist.com</webMaster>
    <managingEditor>rondiorio@economist.com</managingEditor>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <docs>http://www.economist.com/rss/</docs>
    <item>
      <title>France’s public finances: The belt-tightener-in-chief</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111112_EUP002_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Beans on toast for dinner?&lt;/span&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;SHORTLY after he was elected president in 2007, Nicolas Sarkozy marched uninvited into a meeting of European Union finance ministers in Brussels to declare that France was postponing by two years its commitment to balance its budget. Even as the financial crisis set in a year later, he banned the term “austerity”, a word that was said to scare the faint-hearted French. But now, with France’s AAA credit rating still on the line, Mr Sarkozy is reinventing himself as a champion of fiscal prudence.On November 7th the government unveiled its second austerity plan in three months. This one promises savings worth an extra €7 billion ($9.5 billion) in 2012, on top of the €11 billion announced at an emergency budget meeting in August. The new measures do not alter the timing of France’s plan for the public finances: the deficit should still fall to 4.5% of GDP next year, and 3% in 2013. But the faltering economy means France needs an extra effort in order to meet these targets. In an interview last month, Mr Sarkozy conceded that GDP growth in 2012 would reach...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538219?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538219</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 13:18:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in the ex-Yugoslavia: Broadcasting to the Balkans</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111112_EUP004_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Milic is coming to a screen near you&lt;/span&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;IN THE centre of Sarajevo, Bosnia’s capital, a gleaming piece of Arabic script adorns the top of a new building. This is the logo of Al Jazeera, the Qatari network that has changed the face of television news since it was founded 15 years ago. Inside the building, carpenters and technicians are putting the finishing touches to the offices. But this is not just another foreign bureau.Al Jazeera’s Balkan service goes live on November 11th. This will be the second foreign-language station the network has opened, after Al Jazeera English in 2006. But what language is it? Journalists will be broadcasting in “their” language, say station bosses. This tongue used to be called Serbo-Croatian; now it goes by a number of names: Serbian, Croatian, Bosnian or Montenegrin. (Think New Zealand, Scottish and American versions of English.) The target audience for the channel will be the former Serbo-Croatian speaking regions of the ex-Yugoslavia. But plenty of Macedonians and Slovenes understand the language, as do older Kosovo Albanians.Tarik Djodjic, the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538213?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538213</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 13:18:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azerbaijan: How to spend it</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111112_EUM974.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WALK along the shore of the Caspian sea in Azerbaijan’s capital, Baku, and you smell oil in the air. You can also see it, or rather its effects: in the marble balustrade along a wide promenade, in the floodlit fountains, in the Tiffany and Gucci boutiques, in the London black cabs (repainted purple) ordered by the government, and in a vast state flag atop the tallest flagpole in the world, flying over the site where the arena for next year’s Eurovision song contest is being built.An oil windfall since the main export pipeline began operations in 2006 has transformed an unloved Soviet city into a glitzy capital, often with locals evicted from their houses. The oil money has entrenched an autocratic and corrupt political system that is resistant to change.Azerbaijan is run by Ilham Aliyev. He inherited the presidency from his late father, Heydar, a shrewd KGB general who had also run Azerbaijan in Soviet times. When the son took over in 2003 many saw him as a Moscow-educated “golden youth” who lacked his father’s skills. But in the past few years he has consolidated power, suppressed opposition, eliminated...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538212?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538212</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 13:17:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greece’s dysfunctional politics: Tomorrow and tomorrow</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111112_EUP007_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;IT TOOK several days of back-and-forth talks, missed deadlines and public and private outrage, but Greece finally has a new prime minister. On November 10th Lucas Papademos, a former vice-president of the European Central Bank, was named to replace George Papandreou, who had pledged to stand down four days earlier. The decision meant Greece had come full circle in less than a working week: on November 7th Mr Papademos had looked like a shoo-in for the job before negotiations went sour.It may have taken a while to reach, but the choice at least looks sensible. Mr Papademos, an academic economist and a member of no political party, has the reputation to reassure Greece’s bail-out partners, and his financial expertise should prove useful when it comes to implementing the complexities of the looming 50% haircut private holders of Greece’s bonds must suffer, under a deal struck in Brussels on October 26th.The last casualty of this week’s wrangling was Philippos Petsalnikos, the speaker of parliament. A German-speaker skilled at keeping Greek lawmakers in order, he looked like a dead certainty to replace Mr...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538217?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538217</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 13:17:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany’s economy: A case of the sniffles</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20111112_EUD001_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;MUCH of Europe has pneumonia. How is that affecting Germany, the continent’s biggest economy? Exports are surprisingly buoyant considering the European pandemonium; they rose by 0.9% in September. But industrial production dropped by 2.7% in September and new orders, a harbinger of future output, fell by 4.3%, the third monthly decline in a row.Business is bracing for harder times. Expectations have been falling since February, according to the Ifo Business Survey. The biggest problem is the euro crisis, which is playing havoc with Germany’s trading partners. Industrial orders from the euro zone plunged by 12.1% in September. Demand will also wane from Asia and eastern Europe, which have been Germany’s fastest-growing markets. Exports make up around half of the country’s GDP, so a slowdown is inevitable. On November 9th the government’s advisory council of economic “wise men” predicted that growth would shrink from 3% this year to 0.9% in 2012. They expect near-stagnation until the middle of 2012. Some pundits think the economy will shrink.This may look like poetic justice to peripheral euro-zone countries, which...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538183?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538183</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 12:32:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nagorno-Karabakh: Conflict on ice</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111112_EUP003_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;372&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;It’s lovely in the summer&lt;/span&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;“I AM almost full for next summer”, boasts Mike Aghjayan, an Armenian from Lebanon who is managing a new hotel in the town Azeris call Shusha and Armenians Shushi. Visitors, mostly diaspora Armenians, will come from the United States, Canada, France, Russia, Lebanon and Iran. In 1988 this was a pleasant hilltop town, home to 15,000. Today barely 4,000 live on amid the ruins of war. His guests, Mr Aghjayan explains, “want to see the land people gave their blood for.”Nagorno-Karabakh is often described as one of several post-Soviet “frozen conflicts”. However, as the war in 2008 between Russia and Georgia over the breakaway territory of South Ossetia showed, ice can melt quickly. In Soviet times Nagorno-Karabakh was a mostly Armenian-populated autonomous enclave inside Azerbaijan, some 4,000 square kilometres (1,540 square miles) big. Conflict erupted in 1988 as the territory’s Armenians sought to secede from Azerbaijan. By the time the war ended in 1994, the victorious Armenians had doubled the enclave’s size and carved out a land corridor to Armenia...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538216?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538216</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 11:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlemagne: Europe against the people?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/articles/20111112_EUD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;EUROPE has claimed the scalps of two leaders in almost as many days. First George Papandreou, the Greek prime minister, promised to resign, and then Italy’s Silvio Berlusconi did the same. Both leaders have been in trouble for some time, but the immediate cause of their downfall is plain: the ultimatum they received from euro-zone leaders at the G20 summit in Cannes to reform their economies—or else.Mr Papandreou was instructed to approve the last European bail-out deal or risk losing his loans and being ejected from the euro. He scrapped his call for a referendum, and agreed on November 6th to make way for a government of national unity. With Italy’s bond yields reaching danger levels, Mr Berlusconi was told he lacked credibility and was made to “invite” the IMF to supervise his reforms. On November 8th, though, Mr Berlusconi lost his majority in parliament, and agreed to step down once the reforms are passed.Two taboos were broken in Cannes. It was the first time euro-zone leaders accepted that a member could default and leave the euro. (And once the unthinkable is possible, why stop at Greece?) It was also the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21538204?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21538204</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 November 2011 11:18:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy’s government: Hands off our pensioni</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THIS week Umberto Bossi, leader of the Northern League, the junior partner in Silvio Berlusconi’s coalition, told a reporter who approached him politely that she was “irritating the fuck out of” them and should “piss off”. He had a similar message for the euro zone.On October 23rd, in Brussels for a euro-zone summit, Mr Berlusconi received a ticking-off from Angela Merkel, Germany’s chancellor, and Nicolas Sarkozy, the French president, for not doing enough to guarantee the stability of Italy’s public finances (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/node/21534815&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Charlemagne&lt;/a&gt;). In response he hit on the idea of scrapping a prized facet of his country’s welfare system. Italians can retire before pensionable age if they have contributed for long enough to the state welfare system: from 55 (if they have contributed for 40 years) or from 60 (for 36 years).But Mr Bossi vetoed the plan, hinting that it could tear the government apart. Mr Berlusconi was left to return to Brussels with a letter that promised much but guaranteed little. It included pledges to raise the normal retirement age to 67 by 2026 (the previous plan was to reach 65 by the same date); sell off assets worth €15 billion ($21 billion); and make it easier for employers to sack workers in a crisis.Why did Mr Bossi take such a hard line? Local elections in May showed that the Northern League was...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21534826?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21534826</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greece and the euro: Papandreou’s people</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/20111105_EUP001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;“WE SHOUT outside parliament, we call the politicians thieves and traitors, but they don’t take any notice, they just go on letting us down,” said Alexis Anagnostopoulos, an unemployed welder, after hearing about this week’s plan by George Papandreou, his prime minister, to hold a referendum in December on the euro crisis. Yet as it turns out he and other angry Greeks may not even get to vote.A first hurdle was a vote of confidence to endorse Mr Papandreou’s proposed plebiscite. By the end of the week it seemed unlikely that his Panhellenic Socialist Movement (Pasok) could muster the required 151 votes and thus that he would even keep his job. After the October 2009 election Pasok had 160 seats in the 300-seat parliament. At the start of the week it had 152, but several more deputies promptly broke ranks. The most likely outcome as we went to press was a new government of national unity, perhaps led by a technocrat such as a central banker. Or there might be a fresh election.Mr Papandreou had already infuriated Greece’s partners. He announced it without informing them or even his finance minister, Evangelos Venizelos, who conveniently...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21536667?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21536667</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ireland and the euro: Pig no more?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UNDER Ireland’s austerity plans, tax rises and spending cuts worth a cumulative €30 billion ($41 billion), the equivalent of 20% of a single year’s GDP, will be imposed over the seven years to 2014. Pay and welfare cuts, as well as higher taxes, have all taken their toll on output. House prices have fallen by 43% from their 2007 peak. A year ago the cost of rescuing the banks forced the government led by Fianna Fail’s Brian Cowen to seek a European Union/IMF bail-out worth some €85 billion.After this it was no surprise that Mr Cowen lost February’s election to Fine Gael’s Enda Kenny. Mr Kenny now heads a centrist coalition with Labour that has Ireland’s biggest-ever parliamentary majority. He hopes that Ireland will be the first to exit its EU/IMF bail-out programme, ahead of Greece and Portugal. By 2015 he aims to have cut the budget deficit to under 3% of GDP.The country’s painful fiscal adjustment has, so far, been accepted by Irish people with surprising stoicism, despite a rise in unemployment to 14%. The current account swung back into surplus last year; unit labour costs have fallen sharply. Mr Kenny is not short of advice on what to do next. Ireland’s central bank, the OECD and a new Irish fiscal council all have a similar idea: to cut the deficit faster than the EU/IMF programme requires so as to regain market credibility. Ireland could then make an earlier return...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21533445?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21533445</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French politics: Sauce Hollandaise</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/20111022_EUP001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WHEN France’s Socialist Party last won a presidential election, in 1988, Margaret Thatcher governed Britain, Ronald Reagan occupied the White House and Barack Obama was a mere 26-year-old. When it last triumphed at a parliamentary election, in 1997, Tony Blair had just won office for the first time. But there comes a moment when any political party that has been condemned to a long spell in opposition wakes up and does whatever it takes to seize back power. Have the French Socialists reached that point?For the first time in years, the party scents victory. Its newly crowned presidential candidate, François Hollande, was elected on October 16th by 57% of the voters, next to 43% for his second-round rival, Martine Aubry—a big enough margin to give him legitimacy, not so big as to humiliate his opponent. The primary itself, with televised debates and breathless live results on the news channels, gave the Socialists a fresh, modern look. Over 2.8m voters, each of whom paid one euro and pledged allegiance to the “values of the left”, turned out for the run-off.The Socialists have learnt some lessons from their string of defeats. The most...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21533416?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21533416</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine, Russia and the Eurasian Union: Yulia Tymoshenko’s trials</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20111015_EUP001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;SEVEN years ago Yulia Tymoshenko, a populist politician dressed in orange, climbed onto a stage in a snow-covered Kiev and galvanised 150,000 protesters against the rigged victory of Viktor Yanukovych in the 2004 presidential election. She sustained the energy of the crowd for days and ushered Viktor Yushchenko to victory, pledging retribution for those who stood in his way. “Glory to Ukraine”, she hailed; the crowd shouted “Yulia”.Close to the orange revolution’s seventh anniversary, she made headlines again. This time the former prime minister, wearing grey, sat in court to hear a nervous judge reading out a sentence of seven years’ jail, a three-year ban on public office and a fine of $190m as purported compensation for damage allegedly caused when she struck a gas deal with Russia in 2009. The term was symbolic: a year in jail for every one that has passed since the orange revolution.Ever since Ms Tymoshenko was detained in jail on August 5th, the outcome has been predictable. It would have been out of character for Mr Yanukovych, now Ukraine’s thuggishly vindictive president, to let his bitter rival, who has...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21532290?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21532290</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terrorism in Spain: The war is over</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20111029_EUP002_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;A brighter Basque future, with luck&lt;/span&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WHEN ETA broke off a ceasefire in 2007, Jesús Eguiguren, a Basque negotiating on behalf of the Spanish government, warned his separatist counterpart, Francisco Javier López Peña, that his destiny was to spend years in jail. “And you should buy black ties,” Mr López Peña retorted, for the funerals of future victims of the Basque terror organisation.Both men were right. ETA killed ten times over the next three years. Mr Eguiguren was pall-bearer at the funeral of Isaías Carrasco, his friend and fellow Basque Socialist. But in 2008 Mr López Peña, then ETA’s leader, was captured in France.On October 20th, one of Mr López Peña’s successors—believed to be a former lawyer called David Pla—donned a beret and a white face-mask and filmed a statement in which he announced a definitive end to ETA’s 40 years of terrorism. For Spain, it was an historic moment. A bloody campaign that began under Franco’s military dictatorship and claimed 829 lives was finished. “The nightmare is over,” declared Iñigo Urkullu, head of the Basque country’s biggest party, the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21534821?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21534821</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Balkans and Europe: The pull of Brussels</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111015_EUM939.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;IF GOVERNMENTS tweeted what they thought, it would be easy to sum up what those in the western Balkans felt this week: “phew!” from Serbia, “yeah!” from Montenegro and “meh”, the equivalent of shrugged shoulders, from everybody else. Every year the European Commission assesses progress by would-be members of the European Union. It is the day when they “see themselves in the mirror”, comments one diplomat in Brussels, “and the picture is pretty accurate.”This year’s reports, published on October 12th, were awaited impatiently in Serbia and Montenegro. For the Serbs the question was: would the commission recommend that Serbia be made an official EU candidate? Over the past year the government’s strategy has aimed at candidacy by the end of 2011, with a view to using this as a boost in the election next spring.In May, when Serbian police arrested first Ratko Mladic, a former Bosnian Serb general indicted for genocide by the UN war-crimes tribunal in The Hague, and then Goran Hadzic, their final fugitive from international justice, candidate status seemed assured. But Kosovo, which declared independence from...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21532306?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21532306</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Northern Kosovo: Blocked</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SERBIA’S government has lost control of the Serbian-majority north of Kosovo. The roads are barricaded and locals are rowing with NATO peacekeepers and European Union police. Serbia’s president, Boris Tadic, has been pleading with Kosovo Serb mayors to open the roads. In Belgrade, Serbia’s opposition scents his blood.Kosovo’s Serbs have blocked the roads because they want to prevent Kosovo police and customs officers being stationed at two border crossings with Serbia. For them, this would be the first step to accepting Kosovo’s independence, declared in 2008. There are some 120,000 Serbs in Kosovo, about a third of whom live in the north. The rest of Kosovo is dominated by Albanians.To a foreigner a pile of logs on the road is just a barricade. To former Yugoslavs it evokes complex emotions. In 1990 Serbs in the Krajina region of Croatia began their “log revolution”. Blocking roads, they began to carve out a breakaway Serbian statelet. Five years and a war later, they were driven out of Krajina by a victorious Croatian army.It seems unlikely that the logs on Kosovo’s roads will lead to a similar catastrophe. But some analysts are worried that the row could turn nasty. The NATO peacekeeping force, KFOR, wants to clear the barricades. Dozens of protesters have been injured in scuffles, although KFOR has so far refrained from using serious force.The conflict has undermined EU...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21534834?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21534834</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 November 2011 08:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlemagne: A Greek bearing gifts</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20111105_EUD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-full-width&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;“DOES Greece want to remain part of the euro zone, yes or no?” That was the blunt, existential question European leaders put to the Greek prime minister, George Papandreou, when they summoned him to an emergency dinner in Cannes on the eve of the G20 summit to explain his unexpected call for a referendum on the latest deal to salvage the euro. And that is the question they wanted the Greek people to vote on in the hope that the answer might be yes. But that referendum may never take place. As &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;The Economist&lt;/em&gt; went to press, the prime minister’s position seemed untenable, putting the vote into doubt. Much, it must be said, to the relief of some European leaders.Greece does not have much time. Nicolas Sarkozy, the French president, said it would not receive “a single cent” until it had cleared up the uncertainty. Barely a week after their “comprehensive” solution to the euro’s crisis, European leaders must openly consider a chaotic Greek default, and its departure from the euro.Finance ministers are rushing to erect the €1 trillion ($1.4 trillion) firewall that the euro zone had designed at its...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21536665?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21536665</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 November 2011 12:18:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A numerical French obsession: Twenty times twenty</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111105_EUD001_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WORLD leaders and their motorcades will pull up even as the resort of Cannes closes down for the annual G20 summit. It is fitting that France is host, not just because the euro is at the centre of the world’s current economic turmoil, nor yet because Nicolas Sarkozy claims credit for reinventing the group after the 2008 financial crisis. It is also because the French have such a strange fetish for the number 20.Teachers in France in all subjects, even sport, grade students out of 20, as does the school-leaving &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;baccalauréat&lt;/em&gt;. The French language uses 20 as a base for counting between 70 and 100; hence 80 is &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;quatre-vingts&lt;/em&gt; (“four-twenties”). Paris has 20 &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;arrondissements&lt;/em&gt;, or boroughs. The capital’s annual running race is the 20 Kilomètres de Paris. There is a free newspaper called “20 minutes”. Even the main French television news is the Journal de 20 heures (the eight-o’clock news).Jean-Pierre Bourguignon, director of the Institute of Higher Scientific Studies, says numbers like 12 and 60 are more interesting, because they have more...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21536656?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21536656</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 November 2011 11:18:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkish foreign policy: Dormant power revival</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ON A clear day in 2006 Recep Tayyip Erdogan, Turkey’s prime minister, took a leisurely drive along the Turkish-Syrian border with Syria’s president, Bashar Assad, at the wheel. Ahmet Davutoglu, then Mr Erdogan’s foreign-policy adviser, cheerfully translated from the back seat. With 700km (450 miles) of shared border, Syria is central to Mr Davutoglu’s “zero problems with neighbours” policy. Syria, it was hoped, might make a transition from authoritarian dictatorship to Turkish-style democracy in which secularism, piety and the free market happily co-exist. Turkish experts were sent to Damascus to plot this bright future, just as Turkey was trying to mend fences between Syria and Israel.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111105_EUM958_0.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;245&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;Nowadays, Mr Erdogan and Mr Davutoglu hint at military intervention against Mr Assad if he doesn’t stop murdering his own people. The same goes for Israel if it doesn’t stop drilling for gas with the Greek-Cypriots in the east Mediterranean. Friendship with Iran has soured after Turkey agreed to let NATO deploy parts of its missile shield on Turkish soil. Membership talks with the European Union are in effect frozen. So is...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21536653?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21536653</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 November 2011 11:18:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain’s election: Rajoy the reformer</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20111105_EUC887_0.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  class=&quot;imagecache imagecache-290-width&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; /&gt;
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;MARIANO RAJOY, a mild-mannered man destined to be Spain’s next prime minister, says he is confident and ready. But the country his conservative People’s Party (PP) will govern after the election on November 20th is in a bad way. Unemployment has hit 22.6%, and over 5m Spaniards are jobless (see chart). One in nine households has nobody in formal paid employment. Growth is at a halt; a second recession looms.In Castile-La Mancha, officials admit they will overshoot their deficit target by a factor of seven. The outgoing Socialist finance minister, Elena Salgado, insists Spain will meet its target of 6% of GDP this year, but overspending regions (Castile-La Mancha is the worst offender) threaten this, as do flattening tax revenues. Spain’s banks must raise some €26 billion ($36 billion) in new capital by June, a quarter of the total demanded for the euro zone by the European Banking Authority. And they have yet to digest their toxic assets, mostly loans to developers to build on land that is almost worthless or occupied by some of the country’s 700,000 empty homes. The central bank says these problem loans...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21536651?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21536651</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 November 2011 11:18:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wages in Germany: Merkel and the minimum</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT MAY be the opening shot of Angela Merkel’s re-election campaign. Her Christian Democratic Union (CDU) has abandoned one core belief after another (conscription, nuclear power), and is about to do so again. At its convention in Leipzig in mid-November the CDU is likely to back an economy-wide minimum wage.Germany is one of the few European countries to lack a statutory minimum wage. Unions and employers negotiate wages sector by sector. In ten sectors agreed minimums apply to all. But jobs are growing in fragmented services not in manufacturing. Just over half of workers in western Germany are now covered by central agreements; in the east it is only a third. In 2007, 3.7m workers earned under €7 ($9) an hour and 1.2m under €5.The opposition Social Democrats and Greens have long backed a minimum wage. Now CDU leaders have endorsed a plan for a “binding lower limit for wages”, set by an independent body representing unions and employers, similar to Britain’s Low Pay Commission. The expectation is that it will be close to the floor for temporary workers: €7.79 in the west and €6.89 in the east. “This was a movement that came from the bottom up,” says Karl-Josef Laumann, chief of the workers’ branch of the CDU. “If you work for eight hours you should be able to live from your wages.”By embracing a minimum wage Mrs Merkel may deprive the opposition of a vote-winner in the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/node/21536648?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid>http://www.economist.com/node/21536648</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 November 2011 11:18:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
